Register of the Slovak subject collection, 1944-2002
Hoover Institution Archives
Slovak Subject Collection,
1944-2002
XX841
13 manuscript boxes (5.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Serial issues, pamphlets, election campaign literature, other printed matter, and memorabilia, relating to various aspects of twentieth-century Slovak history and politics, including the Soviet invasion of 1968 and the end of the communist regime in 1989; and to post-1989 political, social and economic conditions, and elections, in Slovakia.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Czechoslovakia; Czechoslovakia History Intervention, 1968; Elections Slovakia; Slovakia; Slovakia--History; Slovakia--Politics and government; Slovakia--Economic conditions; Slovakia--Social conditions
Series Description
- SUBJECT FILE, 1918-1994. (Boxes 1-9)
  Pamphlets, booklets, bulletins, newsletters, election campaign material, newspaper issues, magazines, printed matter, official government publications, catalogs, pictorial charts, photo reproductions, and miscellanea, arranged chronologically and then alphabetically by subject
- PERIODICALS, 1989-1992. (Box 9)
  Periodical issues relating to the early period of shaping of new democracy following the 1989 revolution
- MEMORABILIA, 1989-1991. (Box 10)
  Election party pins and stickers
Container List
- SUBJECT FILE, 1918-1994
  - 1918-1938. Publications on the formative years of the Czechoslovak State after WW I and Slovak activist Andrej Hlinka (Box 1.)
  - 1938-1945. "Opressor and Opressed: The Slovak Republic, 1939-1945" by Nina Jurewicz. Typescript, 1991
  - 1968 Soviet Intervention
    - August 69 na Slovensku. Printed photo-album, 1990
    - Komunisticka Strana Slovenska. Minutes and resolutions from extra-ordinary party congress, August 26-29. Typescript
  - 1968-1989
    - Milan Simecka. Predbezna bibliografie za leta 1975-1990. Pamphlet
    - Slovak-Australian Monitor. Emigre quarterly publication on contemporary Slovak history. Nos 8-11, 1985. Mimeograph
  - 1989 Revolution. Appeal to Communist authorities for political and social reforms (typescript); commemorative printed matter on 1989 events; and fliers, 1990
  - 1989-
    - Catholic church. John Paul II. Poster from his trip to Slovakia
    - Civic liberties. Academic freedom at Trnava University. Fliers and correspondence, 1992
    - Ecological movement. Independent publications of non-governmental organizations on state of ecology in Slovak Republic. Ochranca Prirody, 1986-1989; Dunai, 1988-1990, and other printed matter (Box 2)
    - Government. Ministerial releases, documents on strategic economic plans, statistical data for 1991-1992; analysis and proposals on internal policies, catalogue on business opportunities, and other printed matter (Box 3)
    - Labor Unions, 2-nd congress, June 1993. Copies of documents
    - Leftist coup d'etat, Threat of. Newspaper issues, 1991
    - Political parties (Box 4)
      - General
        - General
        - Ceskoslovenska Strana Socialisticka
        - Demokraticka Strana
        - Hnutie Ceskoslovenskoho Porozumenia
        - Hnutie za Demokkraticke Slovensko
        - Krestansko Demokraticke Hnutie
        - Nationalistic groups
        - Obcianska Demokraticka Unia
        - Slovenska Narodna Strana
        - Socialnodemokraticka Strana na Slovensku
        - Strana Slobody (Box 5)
        - Verejnost Proti Nasiliu
      - Elections
        - 1990
          - General
          - Analysis
        - 1992 (Box 6)
          - General
          - Political parties
            - General
            - Hnutie za Slobodu Prejavu
            - Hungarian Minority
            - Krestansko Demokraticke Hnutie
            - Obcianska Demokraticka Strana- Demokraticka Strana
            - Obcianska Demokraticka Unia
            - Slovenska Ludova Strana
            - Socialnodemokraticka Strana na Slovensku
            - Strana Demokratickej Lavice
            - Strana Zelenych
        - 1994 (Box 7)
          - General
          - Political parties
            - Demokraticka Strana
            - Demokraticka Unia Slovenska
            - Hungarian minority
            - Krestanska Socialna Unia Slovenska
            - Krestansko Demokraticke Hnutie
            - Slovenska Narodna Strana
            - Strana Demokratickej Lavice
          - Voting ballots
      - Minorities (Box 8)
        - Hungarian
          - General
          - Independent Hungarian Initiative
        - Ukrainian
    - Privatization. Brochures, fliers, newspapers, official government releases
      - General
      - Plan
        - 1991
        - 1994
      - Vouchers
    - Public opinion
      - Bulletin of government statistical office
        - 1990
        - 1992
      - Socio-political surveys. Publications of government sponsored projects (Box 9)
        - Church, Position of, 1991
        - Culture, Situation of national, 1991
        - Current political issues
          - 1991
          - 1992
          - 1994
        - Privatization, 1991
        - Socio-economic transformation, 1991
        - Women, Situation of, 1991
    - Student movement, 1988-1989. Appeals, declarations. Fliers and typescripts
- PERIODICALS, 1989-1992.
  - Periodical issues relating to the early period of shaping of new democracy following the 1989 revolution (Box 9.)
- MEMORABILIA, 1989-1991.
  - Election party pins and stickers. Please see card catalog for increments that may have been received after December 1994 (Box 10)
- INCREMENTAL MATERIALS (Box 11-13)
  This addition to the collection has not yet been described. Please let the Hoover Institution Archives know if you would like to see this material described.